Séon O'Shannon

Developer | Manager



seon@eons.llc



+1 (775) 354-4343



Reno, NV



https://eons.llc

About me ——

From business to biotech to de novo AI to cloud native software, my breadth of experience allows me to easily cross disciplines and bring people together. Building strong teams and resilient communities is something I continuously strive for. Whether I get to learn a new programming language, backdoor broken servers, design hardware, or build new organisms, I'm always excited to dig into interesting problems with good people and come back with novel solutions. I believe we have a responsibility to work together to leave this world better than we found it.

Skills*

Leadership

C++

Python

Web (PHP, JS, CSS, HTML)

Cloud Architecture

Embedded Systems

Hardware & Electrical Engineering

Linux

Windows

Devops + CI/CD

Git / Version Control

Security

Experiment Design & Debugging

*Confidence over perceived growth

Experience

2022-now Senior Software Engineer

Zywave

For Zywave, I help lead a team focused on delivering a great user experience for comparative insurance quoting. This work includes web development, solutions architecture, data management, and devops.

2021-2022 Solutions Architect

AOE Greens

For AOE Greens, I provided the custom software and cloud infrastructure for controlling hydroponics hardware through a secure web interface. Besides business strategy, the CEO and I collaborated on the design of hardware, circuits, software, and UI/UX for a fully custom IoT solution.

2020-now Founder & CEO

eons LLC

For my own business, I architect, implement, maintain, and secure our cloud environment and frameworks for ops, AI, and data management. My work includes everything from hardware assembly through vpn & firewall implementation to Kubernetes management and web development. I also handle our budgets and keep our clients happy.

2017-2021 Research Associate

Zeakal

I worked on a genetic engineering pipeline and managed other personnel, equipment, greenhouses, labs, and reagents. Using both Excel and Python, I wrote and mathematically verified software for automating the digestion of experimental data, enabling faster time-to-results across numerous studies. For collaboration with our global team, I built and hosted data servers for research results.

2015-2019 Lead Software Engineer

Brain2Bo

Using C++, Qt, & novel neuroscience I designed, developed, and deployed a cross-platform software solution for building brains. I built wired, and wrote drivers for PWM, SPI, & I2C modules to create robot pets.

Education

2013-2017

B.S. Biochemistry & Molecular Biology University of Nevada, Reno Thesis: "Overexpression of DGAT1 and Modified Cysteine Soy Oleosin Increases Oil Content in the Green Tissue of *Arabidopsis*

thaliana", also earned a minor in mathematics.

GPA: 3.402

Achievements

2016 Secretary & Director

Reno Video Game Symphony

Designed & implemented a constitution for the Reno Video Game Symphony and made the organization 501(c)(3) nonprofit.

Eagle Scout

Boy Scouts of America

Eagle scout project was painting a map of the United States at Virginia

Palmer Elementary School.

Latest

2014

Get the latest version of this resume at https://github.com/eons44/resume.doc References are available upon request (they will not be stored on the public repo).